<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>



<text>
<![CDATA[  
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>The interdisciplinary Graduate Group in Comparative Biochemistry administers the PhD degree for students interested in a biochemical and molecular approach to problems in the biological sciences. Students work under the supervision of faculty from diverse disciplines, including Molecular and Cell Biology; Nutritional Science and Toxicology; Plant and Microbial Biology; Chemistry; Chemical Engineering; Environmental Science, Policy, and Management; Public Health; as well as the Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory.</p>
<h3>Undergraduate Program</h3>
<p>There is no undergraduate program in Comparative Biochemistry.</p>
<h3>Graduate Program</h3>
<p><a href="/archive/2017-18/graduate/degree-programs/comparative-biochemistry/">Comparative Biochemistry</a>: PhD</p>
  
]]>
</text>
<coursestext>
<![CDATA[
<h3>Comparative Biochemistry</h3>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">COMPBIO 294</span> 
<span class="title">Comparative Biochemistry Seminar</span> 
<span class="hours">1 Unit</span>
</h3>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2018, Fall 2017, Fall 2016<br/>
The objective of this course is to provide an overview of the research activities conducted by faculty members of the Graduate Group in Comparative Biochemistry. The lectures will cover a wide range of interdisciplinary research topics reflecting the breadth of the Group. An important goal of this course is to enhance intellectual and collaborative interactions between students and faculty of the Graduate Group by increasing awareness of the range</span><span class="deschide"> of research projects. The course will be conducted in a seminar format and is required for students new to the Graduate Group. It is also recommended for advanced students currently in the Group.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Comparative Biochemistry Seminar:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="404" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1 hour of seminar per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Comparative Biochemistry/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Comparative Biochemistry Seminar:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">COMPBIO 299</span> 
<span class="title">Graduate Research</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 12 Units</span>
</h3>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2018, Spring 2018, Fall 2017<br/>
Graduate student research.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Graduate Research:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="704" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing in the Comparative Biochemistry Graduate Group</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-12 hours of independent study per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> <br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"></span>6 weeks - 2.5-30 hours of independent study per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"></span>8 weeks - 1.5-22.5 hours of independent study per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Comparative Biochemistry/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Graduate Research:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div></div>
]]>
</coursestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><p class="facitem"><strong>+ </strong>Indicates this faculty member is the recipient of the Distinguished Teaching Award.</p><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Steven Brenner, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Molecular biology, computational biology, evolutionary biology, bioengineering, structural genomics, computational genomics, cellular activity, cellular functions, personal genomics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14469"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>George A. Brooks, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Exercise &amp; environmental physiology, metabolism, lactate shuttle, crossover concept, lactate, lactic acidosis, traumatic brain injury, obesity, diabetes, the Warburg Effect in cancer, aging biology, isotope tracer technology, arterial-venous difference measurements, clamp technology, muscle biopsies, cell culture, mitochondrial biogenesis, energy substrate partitioning, carbohydrate metabolism, lipid metabolism, fatty acid reesterification, menopause.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14171"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Bob B. Buchanan, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Biotechnology, environmental policy, plant biology, thioredoxin.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14407"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>John E. Casida, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Pesticides, insect biology, environmental science, pest management, molecular toxicology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14483"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Peter H. Duesberg, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Genetic structure of retroviruses, carcinogenesis, aneuploidy, virology, HIV-AIDS.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13885"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Lin He, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ian Holmes, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Computational biology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/ian-holmes"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sung-Hou Kim, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Computational genomics, Structural Biology, drug discovery, disease genomics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14921"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jack F. Kirsch, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Enzymology, directed evolution, drug discovery.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14926"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Isao Kubo, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Agriculture, insect biology, pest management.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14938"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>John Kuriyan, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Structural and functional studies of signal transduction, DNA replication, cancer therapies, phosphorylation.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13895"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Lexin Li, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Stuart M. Linn, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Biology, enzymology of DNA metabolism, DNA repair and replication in mammalian cells, mechanisms of DNA damage by reactive oxygen species, structure of iron: DNA complexes, DNA damage and repair, DNA polymerases.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15063"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Fenyong Liu, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Public health, infectious diseases.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15029"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Anastasios Melis, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Photosynthesis, Metabolic Engineering, bioenergy.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15342"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Daniel S. Rokhsar, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Biology, collective phenomena and ordering in condensed matter and biological systems, theoretical modeling, computational modeling, behavior of quantum fluids, cold atomic gases, high temperature superconductors, Fermi and Bose systems.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15276"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Randy W. Schekman, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Saccharomyces cerevisiae, organelle assembly, intracellular protein transport, assembly of cellular organelles, Alzheimer's Disease.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13908"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Barry Shane, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Plant biology, health and nutrition, nutritional sciences and toxicology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15665"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Martyn T. Smith, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Cancer, genomics, toxicology, molecular epidemiology, exposome.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15044"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Yun Song, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Computational biology, population genomics, applied probability and statistics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14178"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Hei Sook Sul, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Plant biology, health and nutrition, nutritional sciences &amp; toxicology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15684"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Christopher D. Vulpe, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Genetics, genomics, ecotoxicology, gene expression, water quality, copper, iron, toxicology, susceptibility, environmental, ecotoxicogenomics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15587"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Nir Yosef, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Computational biology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/nir-yosef"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><h4>Emeritus Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Bruce N. Ames, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Molecular biology, cancer, aging, mitochondrial decay, oxidants and antioxidants, micronutrient deficiencies and DNA damage, chronic inflammation and cancer.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14339"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Nancy Amy, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Nutritional science and toxicology, nutrition, cell metabolism, trace elements.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14374"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>George W. Chang, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Microbial biology, health and nutrition, food safety.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14489"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ben De Lumen, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Cancer prevention, academic enterpreneurship.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14535"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Montgomery Slatkin, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Evolutionary theory, genetic evolution, natural populations of plants and animals populations, human populations, natural selection structure genomes.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15458"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

