<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>



<text>
<![CDATA[  
 <h3><span>Guidelines for Quantitative Reasoning Courses</span></h3> <ul> 	<li>A letter grade of C- or better is required.</li> 	<li>Variable unit self-paced courses approved for Quantitative Reasoning must be taken for the full unit value of the regular course.</li> 	<li>Courses fulfilling the Quantitative Reasoning requirement may not be applied to other College breadth requirements.</li> 	<li>Beginning fall 2015, courses must be at least three units in value.</li> </ul> <h3>Satisfying the Quantitative Reasoning Requirement while in High School</h3> <ul> 	<li>SAT I: Reasoning Test—600</li> 	<li>SAT II: Subject Test, Math Level II 	<ul> 		<li>Test date before May 1995: 550</li> 		<li>Test date May 1995 or later: 520</li> 	</ul> 	</li> 	<li>ACT—28, on math portion</li> 	<li>Advanced Placement Exams in Calculus AB or BC—score of 3, 4, or 5</li> 	<li>Advanced Placement Exam in Computer Science AB—score of 3, 4, or 5</li> 	<li>Advanced Placement Exam in Statistics—score of 3, 4, or 5</li> 	<li>International Baccalaureate Higher Level Exam in Mathematics or Computer Science score of 5, 6 or 7</li> 	<li>A-level Mathematics Exam—grade of A, B, or C</li> </ul> <h3>Satisfying the Quantitative Reasoning Requirement at Berkeley</h3> <p>With course work: The following courses satisfy the Quantitative Reasoning requirement. (Note: Most students who have not fulfilled the requirement prior to admission choose either Mathematics 32 or Statistics 2 to fulfill Quantitative Reasoning.)</p> <ul> 	<li>Any 3-unit course in the Math department (except 10, 15, 24, 39, 39A-Z, 49, 84, 88, 96, 98, 98BC, 99, 103, 160, 197, 198, 198BC, 199)</li> 	<li>Any 3-unit course in the Statistics department (except 0PX, 24, 39, 39A-Z, 88, 89A, 94, 97, 98, 99, 100, 197, 198, 199)</li> 	<li>Any 3-unit course in the Computer Science department (except 9A-Z, 24, 39, 39A-Z, 88, 98, 99, 146C, 194, 195, 197, 198 or 199)</li> 	<li>Information C8</li> </ul> <p>By exam: A score of 26 or better on the <a href="http://math.berkeley.edu/programs/undergraduate" target="_blank">Quantitative Reasoning exam</a> offered by the Math Department at the beginning of each semester will satisfy the requirement. </p> <h3>Satisfying the Quantitative Requirement with Transfer Work</h3> <ul> 	<li>Transfer courses must be taken on a letter-graded basis and be completed with a grade of C- or better. At schools where an equivalent articulated course is offered only on a Passed/Not Passed basis, a Passed grade will be accepted in fulfillment of the requirement.</li> 	<li>For courses from California community colleges, review <a href="http://www.assist.org" target="_blank">ASSIST</a>. Note: <a href="http://www.universityofcalifornia.edu/admissions/transfer/requirements/additional-requirements/igetc/index.html" target="_blank">IGETC certification</a> from a California community college or a letter of reciprocity from a UC campus satisfies the Quantitative Reasoning requirement (and all other L&amp;S breadth requirements).</li> </ul>
  
]]>
</text>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

