<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>



<text>
<![CDATA[  
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">RDEV 200</span> 
<span class="title">Principles of Sustainable Real Estate Development</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Not yet offered<br/>
Addresses the needs and challenges of developing sustainable urban communities through multi-disciplinary real estate development approaches, which confront the social, economic, cultural and environmental conditions facing contemporary cities in the United States and throughout the world. The course develops a conceptual foundation that allows students to define goals and metrics for sustainable development principles amidst the complex social-environmental dynamics</span><span class="deschide"> that constitute large urban development in cities. Approaches to sustainable development and building will range from planning related issues such as smart growth, urban infill and healthy city policies, tactical urbanism, civic engagement and “smart cities.”</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Principles of Sustainable Real Estate Development:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="65" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 6 weeks - 6 hours of lecture per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Real Estate Development + Design/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Principles of Sustainable Real Estate Development:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">RDEV 210</span> 
<span class="title">Introduction to Development Economics &amp; Fundamentals</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Not yet offered<br/>
This course teaches students the fundamentals of real estate development finance and economics. Grounded in an understanding of urban economics in large cities, the class will examine the factors in national, regional and local real estate markets that determine development needs and opportunities. Financial analysis skills and analytical processes will be developed for evaluating private and public sector development and investment sources employed across all</span><span class="deschide"> major property classes and land uses. The class will discuss aspects of financial feasibility throughout the scope of the development process from market and predevelopment analysis and site selection to lease-up or sales of the final product.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Introduction to Development Economics &amp; Fundamentals:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="103" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Objectives  Outcomes</strong></p><p><strong>Course Objectives:</strong> Acquire an understanding of the economic and market impacts of different real estate development product types<br/>Develop critical financial analysis skills and knowledge to evaluate real estate development markets and opportunities<br/>Gain financial knowledge and principles which support sustainable and more equitable real estate development<br/>Understand how urban economics and investment markets impact urban land and real estate development production and viability</p></div>

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 6 weeks - 6 hours of lecture per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Real Estate Development + Design/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Introduction to Development Economics &amp; Fundamentals:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">RDEV 220</span> 
<span class="title">Real Estate Development Finance</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Not yet offered<br/>
Fundamentals of real estate development finance. Financial analysis skills and analytical tools for evaluating private and public development and investment in real estate, over all product types. Site selection, market analysis, financial feasibility, design and legal considerations, construction, lease-up, operations, and property sales. Decision-making scenarios to evaluate and assess development concepts and project viability. Funding sources for market rate</span><span class="deschide"> and affordable development.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Real Estate Development Finance:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="878" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Real Estate Development + Design/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Real Estate Development Finance:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">RDEV 230</span> 
<span class="title">Public-Private Partnerships, Strategies, and Tools</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Not yet offered<br/>
Public-private partnerships have emerged as a key means of real estate development across the United States. Governments, both local and regional, have real estate assets but they often need private partners to catalyze and execute projects. The course will explore the tools, strategies and partnerships used to implement such projects and pay special attention to the transaction and financing of such developments. The class will teach students the skills and knowledge</span><span class="deschide"> to manage the complex and often competing agendas of parties involved in public-private partnerships in real estate development.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Public-Private Partnerships, Strategies, and Tools:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="110" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Real Estate Development + Design/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Public-Private Partnerships, Strategies, and Tools:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">RDEV 240</span> 
<span class="title">Professional Practice of Real Estate Development</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Not yet offered<br/>
Fundamental practices in private, public, and non-profit real estate development. Perspectives of project managers, investment specialists, bankers and lawyers, architects, planners, contractors and property managers representing companies from around the Bay Area following the life cycle/sequence of a real estate project. Approaches to understanding and incorporating community perspectives. Familiarity with professional work products, contracts, schedules and</span><span class="deschide"> documents handled or produced by practitioners on a daily basis as course materials.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Professional Practice of Real Estate Development:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="438" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Real Estate Development + Design/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Professional Practice of Real Estate Development:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">RDEV 280</span> 
<span class="title">Capstone Project</span> 
<span class="hours">2 Units</span>
</h3>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Not yet offered<br/>
In this course you will conduct an original investigation in order to acquire new knowledge within a framework set by a client in practice. The primary goal of this research class is to deepen your personal understanding of a particular topic or issue in real estate development. A key secondary goal is to help address a practical aim or objective of your client.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Capstone Project:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="858" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Real Estate Development + Design/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Capstone Project:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div></div>
  
]]>
</text>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

