<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>



<text>
<![CDATA[  
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>The PhD program in Molecular Toxicology focuses on the adverse effects of chemicals on living organisms and how these effects are modulated by genetic, physiologic, and environmental factors.</p>
<h3>Graduate Program</h3>
<p><a href="/2017-18/graduate/degree-programs/molecular-toxicology/">Molecular Toxicology</a>: PhD</p>
  
]]>
</text>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><p class="facitem"><strong>+ </strong>Indicates this faculty member is the recipient of the Distinguished Teaching Award.</p><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>John E. Casida, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Pesticides, insect biology, environmental science, pest management, molecular toxicology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14483"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Danica Chen, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Aging, stem cell, diseases of aging.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14611"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Brenda Eskenazi, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Public health, epidemiology, biostatistics, maternal &amp; child health.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14640"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>+ Gary L. Firestone, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Cancer, steroid hormones, molecular endocrinology, tumor biology, growth factors, dietary compounds, tumor cells, glucocorticoids.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13887"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>+ Tyrone Hayes, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Genetics, amphibians, developmental endocrinology, steroid hormones, metamorphosis, sex differentiation, hormonal differentiation, African clawed frog, Japnanes Kajika, Pine Barrens treefrog.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14815"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Isao Kubo, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Agriculture, insect biology, pest management.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14938"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Fenyong Liu, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Public health, infectious diseases.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15029"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sheng Luan, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Microbial biology, plant biology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15325"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Daniel K. Nomura, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Chemical biology, metabolism, toxicology, cancer.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16349"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Barry Shane, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Plant biology, health and nutrition, nutritional sciences and toxicology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15665"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Martyn T. Smith, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Cancer, genomics, toxicology, molecular epidemiology, exposome.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15044"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Norman Terry, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Phytoremediation, Bioremediation, environmental cleanup, soil and water, plant biology, microbial biology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15354"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Christopher D. Vulpe, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Genetics, genomics, ecotoxicology, gene expression, water quality, copper, iron, toxicology, susceptibility, environmental, ecotoxicogenomics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15587"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jen-Chywan (Wally) Wang, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Steroid hormones, glucocorticoids, molecular physiology, Metabolic Diseases.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15597"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

