<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>



<text>
<![CDATA[  
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>An interdepartmental group of faculty members — from the Department of Environmental Science, Policy, and Management (ESPM) and related departments at UC Berkeley — administers the Range Management Masters program. The program prepares students with a bachelor's degree in resource management or related disciplines to pursue advanced work. Graduate study leads to a Master of Science degree that serves as the basis for a professional career in rangeland management. Fields of specialization include grassland, savanna, and shrubland ecology, rangeland rehabilitation, wetland ecology, and rangeland policy.</p>
<p><span>Doctoral work in range management may be pursued as part of the PhD program in ESPM.</span></p>
<h3><span>Undergraduate Program</span></h3>
<p><span>There is no undergraduate program in Range Management.</span></p>
<h3><span>Graduate Program</span></h3>
<p><span><a href="/2017-18/graduate/degree-programs/range-management/">Range Management</a>: MS</span></p>
  
]]>
</text>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><p class="facitem"><strong>+ </strong>Indicates this faculty member is the recipient of the Distinguished Teaching Award.</p><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Barbara H. Allen-Diaz, <i>Professor and Russell Rustici Chair in Rangeland Management</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Reginald H. Barrett, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Environmental science, policy &amp; management, introduced species, species and land use ecology, land use planning, terrestrial vertebrates, human impact on wildlife, tule elk, wild pigs.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14411"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>John J. Battles, <i>Professor</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Steven R. Beissinger, <i>Professor</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Justin S. Brashares, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Wildlife, biodiversity, ecology, conservation, human livelihoods.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14465"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>William E. Dietrich, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Morphology, earth and planetary sciences, geomorphology, evolution of landscapes, geomorphic transport laws, landscape evolution modeling, high resolution laser altimetry, cosmogenic nuclide analysis.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15016"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Mary K. Firestone, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Soils, environmental policy, environmental science, policy &amp; management, wildlife, microbial biology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14669"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>+ Lynn Huntsinger, <i>Professor</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>N. Maggi Kelly, <i>Professor</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Adina M. Merenlender, <i>Adjunct Professor</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Arthur Middleton, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Mary E. Power, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Freshwater ecology, food webs, trophic dynamics, northern California rivers, watersheds.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13874"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>John Radke, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>City and regional planning, landscape architecture and environmental planning, geographic information systems, database design and construction, spatial analysis, pattern recognition computational morphology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15254"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Nathan Sayre, <i>Associate Professor and Chair</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Whendee Silver, <i>Professor</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Scott Stephens, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ian Wang, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong></p><h4>Specialists</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Van Butsic, <i>Assistant Specialist in Cooperative Extension</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Luke T. Macaulay, <i>Assistant Specialist in Cooperative Extension</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Richard B. Standiford, <i>Cooperative Extension Forest Management Specialist</i>. </strong></p><h4>Emeritus Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>James W. Bartolome, <i>Group Chair, Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Plant ecology, grazing, biodiversity, grasslands, environmental science, rangelands, fire, mediterranean ecosystems.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/james-w-bartolome"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Louise P. Fortmann, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>John A. Helms, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>William Z. Lidicker, <i>Professor/Curator Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>+ Joe R. McBride, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Dale R. McCullough, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jeffrey M. Romm, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Thelma E. Rowell, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

