<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>



<text>
<![CDATA[  
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>The Metabolic Biology MS and PhD programs provide interdisciplinary training in the areas that include metabolic regulation, physiological chemistry, nutrient functions, and diseases related to metabolic disorders such as diabetes and cancer.</p>
<h3>Graduate Program</h3>
<p><a href="/2017-18/graduate/degree-programs/metabolic-biology/">Metabolic Biology</a>: MS, PhD</p>
  
]]>
</text>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Gregory W. Aponte, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Health and nutrition, nutritional sciences, signaling between the gut and the brain, neuropeptides, G-protein coupled receptors.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14587"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>John E. Casida, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Pesticides, insect biology, environmental science, pest management, molecular toxicology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14483"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Danica Chen, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Aging, stem cell, diseases of aging.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14611"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Marc Hellerstein, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Plant biology, health and nutrition.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14828"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sona Kang, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Joseph L. Napoli, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Metabolism, nutritional biochemistry, fat-soluble vitamins, retinoids, retinoic acid, retinol, vitamin A, vitamin D, analytical biochemistry.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15165"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Daniel K. Nomura, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Chemical biology, metabolism, toxicology, cancer.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16349"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>James Olzmann, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Ubiquitin, proteasome, lipid droplet, ER-associated degradation, ERAD, metabolism, metabolic disease.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16268"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Barry Shane, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Plant biology, health and nutrition, nutritional sciences and toxicology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15665"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Martyn T. Smith, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Cancer, genomics, toxicology, molecular epidemiology, exposome.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15044"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Andreas Stahl, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Metabolism, obesity, adipose tissue, brown fat, thermogenesis, tissue engineering, diabetes, fatty acid transport, fatty acid, stem cells.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16361"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Hei Sook Sul, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Plant biology, health and nutrition, nutritional sciences &amp; toxicology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15684"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Christopher D. Vulpe, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Genetics, genomics, ecotoxicology, gene expression, water quality, copper, iron, toxicology, susceptibility, environmental, ecotoxicogenomics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15587"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jen-Chywan (Wally) Wang, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Steroid hormones, glucocorticoids, molecular physiology, Metabolic Diseases.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15597"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><h4>Emeritus Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Bruce N. Ames, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Molecular biology, cancer, aging, mitochondrial decay, oxidants and antioxidants, micronutrient deficiencies and DNA damage, chronic inflammation and cancer.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14339"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

